Finding Aid for Graduate Program of Medical and Biological Illustration (University of Michigan) Records and Illustrations
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Neil Hardy Illustrations
  - Hernias of the Vaginal Wall, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. J.G. Ferguson)
  - Nerve Supply, undated (Box 14)
  - Decompensation in Heart Failure, undated (Box 14)
- J. McLaughlin Illustrations, 9 illustrations
  - Aneurysm, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Bassett)
  - Anterior cerebral arteries, undated (Box 14)
  - Anterior cerebral arteries, undated (Box 14)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Ransom)
  - Gauze that is damp with 10% cocaine..., undated (Box 14)
    (Requesting Physician: Drs. Dingman and Natvig)
  - Figures 282 & 283, undated (Box 14)
  - Figures 230-233, undated (Box 14)
  - Region of the Syphysis, undated (Box 14)
  - Region of the Angle (Mandible), undated (Box 14)
  - Condylar process (Mandible), undated (Box 14)
  - Region of the Condylar Process: Submandibular Approach, undated (Box 14)
- Mary Lou Cummings Illustrations
  The Mary Lou Cummings series contains 6 illustrations by Mary Lou Cummings. Cummings was a student of Tom Jones circa 1933-1935 and worked at University of Michigan's University Hospital from circa 1939-1942 and 1953-1959.
  - Colostomy, 1957; Technique: Pen and ink (Box 15)
  - Untitled, 1959 (Box 15)
    (Requesting Physician: Untitled)
  - Untitled, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Placement of Tracheotomy Tube, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Numular Cataract, circa 1955 (Box 15)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. Harold F. Falls, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Experiment on urinary sphincter of a dog, circa 1960 (Box 15)
- Rictor S. Lew Illustrations
  The Rictor S. Lew Illustrations series contains 5 illustrations by Rictor S. Lew. Each of these illustrations shows part of a surgery on the thyroid gland.
  - Orientation of Patient and Endotracheal Tube, 1984; Technique: Pen and Ink (Box 15)
  - Incision for Parathyroid Surgery, 1984; Technique: 3B Carbon Dust, H and HH Carbon Pencils (Box 15)
  - Exposure of Thyroid G, 1984; Technique: 3B Carbon Dust, H and HH Carbon Pencils (Box 15)
  - Retraction of Thyroid Gland and Exposure of Prevetebral Fascia, 1984; Technique: 3B Carbon Dust, H and HH Carbon Pencils (Box 15)
  - Palpating Right Inferior Adenoma and Subsequent Removal, 1984; Technique: 3B Carbon Dust, H and HH Carbon Pencils (Box 15)
- Grant S. Lashbrook Illustrations
  The Grant S. Lashbrook series contains 3 illustrations by Grant S. Lashbrook. Lashbrook studied with Natt C. Jacobs, circa 1957-1959 and worked at University of Michigan's University Hospital from 1959 to 1968.
  - De Lange Syndrome, 1966 (Box 15)
    (Requesting Physician: Dr. H. F. Falls, Department: Ophthalmology, University of Michigan)
  - Sketch for Procedures for Spasticity, 1966; Technique: Graphite and colored pencil, pastel, watercolor (Box 15)
  - 1 unidentified illustration (Box 15)
- Stephen G. Gilbert Illustrations, 10 illustrations
  - Abdominal viscera, ventral view, undated (Box 17)
  - The Stomach, Liver, and Spleen, Ventral View (cat), 1968; Technique: Wash on cold pressed illustration board (Box 17)
  - Skull, undated (Box 17)
  - The Female Urogenital System (dog fish), 1970; Technique: Wash on Crescent Illustration Board, cold pressed, surface no. 300 (Box 17)
  - Ventral View of the Dorsal Aorta in a Male, undated (Box 17)
  - Ventral View of the Abdominal Vessels in a Female, undated (Box 17)
  - Fetal Pig, undated (Box 17)
  - Abdominal viscera, ventral view, undated (Box 17)
  - 2 unidentified illustrations (Box 17)
- Miscellaneous Illustrations
  The Miscellaneous Illustrations series contains 28 illustrations by various artists, including: Jean Hirsh (1), Christopher Burke(1), Leon Schlossberg (1), R. Drake (1), M. Croup (2), Tom Jones (1), D. Foster (1), Dennis Lee (1), William L. Brudon (1), W. Branks Stewart (1), Howard Bartner (1), Ida Dox (1), Gottfried Goldenberg (5), M.E. Aitken (1), Fred Harwin (1), Herb Smith (1), Lewis E. Calver (1), Stenstrom (2), Olsen (1), Lopez (1), and two unidentified artists.
  - Miscellaneous Illustrations (Box 18)
- Audiovisual Materials
  The Audiovisual Materials series contains mixed audiovisual materials created by the program. These materials include 38 U-matic tapes, 13 VHS tapes, 1 betacam tape, 4 16 mm films, and 65 slides.
  - 15 U-matic tapes circa, 1983-1991 (Box 19)
  - 15 U-matic tapes circa, 1983-1990 (Box 20)
  - 65 slides of illustrations by Dennis Lee (Box 20)
  - 13 VHS tapes circa, 1985-1996 (Box 21)
  - 8 U-matic tapes circa, 1977-1990 (Box 21)
  - 1 30M tape, undated (Box 21)
  - Tom Jones, Wash Technique (Box 21)
  - Gerald P. Hodge, Pen and Ink (Box 21)
  - University of Michigan Medical TV, Medical Illustration-G. Hodge (Box 21)
  - Untitled 16mm film sent from Medical College of Georgia to Gerald P. Hodge, December 7, 1973 (Box 21)